Are you conscious?
你醒了吗?
Um...
那个...
I'm okay now.
我没事了
I can walk on my own.
我可以自己走
Please put me down.
请放我下来
Are you really all right?
你真的可以吗?
Yes.
是
Good.
那就好
Why are the cherry blossoms blooming? It's midsummer now.
现在明明是盛夏 为什么樱花开了?
That's strange.
好奇怪
I feel like I've seen this before.
让我觉得很熟悉
Finally, you've come.
你们终于来了
Mr. Tsuruki...?
鹤木先生?
I was waiting for you.
我等你们很久了
Welcome to the Usuba house.
欢迎来到薄刃家
Usuba?
薄刃?
MY HAPPY MARRIAGE
剧名:我的幸福婚约
EPISODE 10 SUMMER CHERRY BLOSSOMS, AND THE MISTAKE
第10集:夏之樱花 以及过错
I'm impressed that you found your way here.
真亏你们能找到这里
Um, why Usuba?
请问 薄刃是?
Tsuruki is my pseudonym.
鹤木是化名
Arata... Usuba?
薄刃新?
Yes. I'm part of the same family as you.
没错 我和你同为薄刃血脉
I'm your cousin.
我是你的表亲
From the look of things,
看来你已经知道
you must already have an idea why we came here.
我们来这里的理由吧
To stop Miyo from having nightmares, isn't it?
你是为了终结美世的噩梦对吧?
Miyo's nightmares...
美世的噩梦
The Usuba family's blood is the cause, isn't it?
薄刃的血脉就是原因不是吗?
I won't deny it.
我不否认
But to say it more accurately, the cause of the nightmares is...
更准确的说 噩梦的原因
Miyo's supernatural ability.
是美世的异能
What?
什么?
Are you saying Miyo has a supernatural ability?
你是说美世拥有异能?
Yes. I have no doubt she does.
没错
Not only that, the ability is dangerous and powerful.
不仅如此 她的异能非常强大且危险
N-No. That's impossible.
这是不可能的
Because I was tested for Spirit-Sight and found to be...
因为并没有见鬼之才
You're right. Usually, if you don't have Spirit-Sight,
确实 若是没有见鬼之才
it's a sign you won't develop any supernatural abilities.
一般不能驱使异能
Then I cannot have...
那样一来...
But the Usuba family has a special kind of supernatural abilities.
不过薄刃家的异能特殊
Whether you have Spirit-Sight or not doesn't matter.
跟有无见鬼之才无关
You do have a supernatural ability.
你拥有异能
I am certain of it.
我很肯定
Right, Grandfather?
是吧 祖父?
You resemble your mother, Sumi.
你很像澄美
I'm the head of the Usuba family.
我乃薄刃家家主
My name is Yoshiro Usuba.
薄刃义浪
I'm Sumi Usuba's father,
我是薄刃澄美的父亲
and Miyo, I'm your grandfather.
也是你的祖父 美世
Oh...
这样啊
Aren't you feeling a bit better now since coming to this house?
来了这里后 你有没有感觉好些?
Uh...
什么?
Now that you mentioned it, my body does feel lighter.
这么说来 我确实感觉轻松许多
That's because of Usuba's barrier.
这多亏了薄刃的结界
If you stay in this house,
只要你留在这里
your body should be back to health in no time.
你的身体很快就能复原
What happens if she goes outside of the barrier?
如果她离开这个结界呢?
Will she start having nightmares again?
又会做噩梦吗?
I reckon she will.
应该会吧
Isn't there a way to release her from her nightmares?
没有能将美世从噩梦中 拯救出来的方法吗?
Of course, there is.
当然有
But if you want Miyo to be saved, there's one condition.
但是要救美世 我有个条件
Huh?
什么?
Kiyoka Kudo,
久堂清霞
will you turn over Miyo to us?
能不能将美世交给我们?
What?
什么?
What on earth is your intention?
你们想干什么?
To us,
对我们来说
Miyo's existence is very special.
美世非常特别
To the Usuba family, she's worth more than anything else.
对于薄刃家 她是无价之宝
If so, why now?
就算真是如此
Why didn't you ask for her before?
为什么时至今日才想要接回她?
Ah... We also didn't think that Miyo would develop a supernatural ability.
我们本以为美世没有异能
However, just recently,
可是最近
we noticed she was showing signs of having supernatural ability.
我们注意到美世拥有异能的迹象
And furthermore, her ability is a rare kind
而且即便是在薄刃家中
among the Usuba family's abilities.
也是非常稀有的异能
What?
什么?
The ability Miyo has is Dream-Sight.
美世拥有的异能是梦见
It's an ability to intervene in people's dreams.
是能够介入他人梦境的能力
The reason why Miyo keeps having nightmares is probably due to
美世噩梦缠身
her Dream-Sight ability.
也是因为梦见的力量
If the Usuba family doesn't directly control it,
如果不交由薄刃家直接管理
someday it will certainly lead to calamities.
可能会招致巨大灾难
That's how dangerous the ability is.
她的能力就是这么可怕
What do you intend to do to Miyo?
你打算对美世做什么?
It's simple.
没你说得这么可怕
We're only trying to return her to where she should be.
只是让她回到她本应该在的地方
As she has developed the ability of Dream-Sight,
只要美世拥有梦见之力
there is no way we can allow her to be outside the Usuba family.
就不能让她离开薄刃家
There's no use in trying to take her away from me.
我不会让你们把美世带离我身边
Mr. Kudo.
久堂先生
Just know that we are giving you this explanation
我们这样跟你解释
as our utmost consideration for you.
是为你着想
Do you really think that I'd say yes to your nonsense?
你们觉得我会答应 你们的一派胡言吗?
Please keep calm.
请冷静一点
This is about the Usuba family.
这是薄刃家的事
- Um-- - Stop joking around.
-请问... -开什么玩笑
Miyo staying with the Usuba family is not possible,
我决不允许美世留在薄刃家
because Miyo is my fiancée.
因为美世是我的未婚妻
- I said this is about the Usuba family. - Um, sir--
-我说了 这是薄刃家的家事 -那个 老爷...
So you are an outsider.
你只是外人
You've been ignoring her this whole time,
你们一直以来放任她不管
but you seek her because you know she has a supernatural ability.
得知她有异能 就要得到她
Do you think such logic will go unchallenged?
你们觉得这讲得通吗?
No matter what, I won't let you have Miyo.
无论发生什么事 我都不会交出美世
I'll protect her.
我会保护她
Do you really think you can protect Miyo?
你真的能保护美世小姐吗?
What?
什么?
During the Saimori family incident,
斋森家那起动乱事件中
you let them kidnap Miyo and she was wounded.
是你任由她被绑架 并让她受了伤
Not only that, you can't stop her from having nightmares,
不仅如此 她现在也是噩梦不断
and you've made her suffer needlessly.
受尽苦痛
Can you honestly say that you are protecting her?
你真的在保护她吗?
Besides, you have more important things to do than being here.
而且你现在还有更重要的事要做吧?
The Grave was opened up.
神墓被打开
We are in the middle of a national crisis.
我们现在身处动摇国家的大事之中
How can you make the time to protect Miyo?
你有时间保护美世吗?
You bastard...!
你这家伙
Because of me, he pushed himself so hard...
因为我 老爷才勉强自己
And I caused him to worry about me...
我让他担心了
What do you want to do, Miyo?
美世 你想要怎么做?
What?
什么?
I...
我...
I don't know.
我不知道
If I said "I want to be with you" now,
如果我现在说“我想要留在你身边”
I would be tying him down forever.
那么老爷或许会被束缚住
I see.
这样啊
So, Mr. Kudo, no amount of talking would help us reach an agreement.
久堂先生 我们既然无法统一意见
Let's do this fairly.
为了公平起见
How about we have a duel and the winner takes Miyo?
我们来决斗 胜者会拥有美世小姐 如何?
A duel?
决斗?
If you win, I will teach you the method to control Miyo's ability.
如果你赢了 我就教你如何控制美世小姐的异能
That way, she won't have to suffer any more nightmares.
这样她也不会再做噩梦
I've never meant for anything like this to happen...
我不是想让你们
A duel for me?
为我决斗...
I accept. I'll take you up on your offer.
我答应你
Thank you.
多谢
Well, then.
那么我们
Shall we have a manly, serious duel?
像男人一样 来一场生死决斗吧
If you win, the Kudo family
如果你赢了 美世会留在久堂家
and if I win, the Usuba family
如果我赢了 美世就要
will become Miyo's home.
留在薄刃家
That goes without saying.
不必多说
I thought I said a serious duel.
我说了这是一场生死决斗
This will suffice.
这就够了
I will not be holding back, you know.
我不会手下留情的
Whoa.
天啊
Too slow.
太慢了
Oops, forgive me.
天啊 真是抱歉
I was aiming for the hilt of your sword but I seem to have missed it.
我本来瞄准了你的刀把 却打偏了
Too bad. You missed too.
可惜 你也打偏了
You certainly are something, as expected.
你确实很了不起
Your supernatural ability is no longer effective on me.
你的异能对我不起作用
Oh, yes. I'll tell you something that's beneficial.
这样啊 那我告诉你一件事吧
In the Usuba family, most of us with supernatural abilities
薄刃家大多数异能者 包括我在内
do not have Spirit-Sight, me included.
都没有见鬼之才
Can you guess why?
你知道这是为什么吗?
Spirit-Sight is necessary when battling Grotesqueries.
见鬼之才在与异形战斗中非常重要
This means, our supernatural abilities are not for battling Grotesqueries.
也就是说 我们的异能不是用来与异形战斗
The abilities that we have
薄刃家的异能
are for battling humans with supernatural abilities.
是为了击败异能者
Like this.
就像这样
What do you think of this?
怎么样?
Aren't you gradually having trouble
你会逐渐
believing what you're seeing?
不相信自己看到的事物 对吧?
You're overconfident.
耍小聪明
Amazing power.
太可怕了
If a wielder of a supernatural ability as powerful as you loses control,
如果像你这样强大的异能者失控
and tries to hurt somebody, would anybody be able to stop them?
并且想要伤人时 谁能阻止你呢?
With Usuba's supernatural abilities...
如果是我们薄刃家的异能
we're the ones that are able
可以直接掌控人心
to manipulate minds directly, we can!
就可以阻止你
This is why the Usuba family has stayed hidden in the shadows of history.
因此薄刃家一直隐藏在历史的阴影中
We have secretly served Mikado
我们秘密受命于帝上
and existed as the ultimate weapon against rogue wielders of supernatural abilities.
作为阻止发狂的异能者的终极武器
What's the matter?
怎么了?
Is that all there is to the Usuba family's supernatural ability?
薄刃的异能就是这种水平吗?
Astonishing.
真是厉害
Nobody has ever reacted at that speed to my illusions.
从没有人能这么快地应对幻觉
It's about time to finish up.
差不多该结束了
I can't let you do that.
不会让你称心如意的
The Usuba family cannot lose to a wielder of supernatural ability.
薄刃家的人不能输给异能者
It's just impossible.
决不能允许这种事发生
As I told you, your illusional ability is no longer effective on me.
我说过 你的幻觉不起作用
Sir, please stop now!
老爷 请住手
You'll be caught in their battle if you get any closer.
你再靠近一点就会被波及
Do you want to die?
你想死吗?
Can you dodge this?
你能躲开这个吗?
It's over.
结束了
Sir!
老爷
I win.
是我赢了
Wait, don't go.
喂 站住
Aren't you going to shoot? I thought this was a serious duel.
你不开枪吗?这是生死决斗吧
I don't need to shoot.
我不必开枪
It's clearly settled.
胜负已分
Sir!
老爷
Miyo!
美世
You are strong.
你很强
But...
不过
protecting Miyo...
保护美世...
Sir!
老爷
Miyo!
美世
That's my job.
是我的责任
Sir...
老爷
The situation is worse than predicted.
情况比预想的还要糟糕
Did another problem arise?
还有其他问题吗?
Yes.
是啊
According to reports,
根据报告
each one of the Grotesqueries has been acting alone until now.
异形们都是单独行动的
But...
但是
now they've started to move in bands.
他们现在是聚集在一起展开行动
That can't be...
这不可能
We need to adapt to their movements
需要针对他们的行动
and change our formations accordingly.
随机应变 变换阵形
Contact Kudo immediately.
现在马上联系久堂
Yes, sir.
遵命
I can't believe it!
我不相信
You just came back here moping after you lost?
你就这样输了 垂头丧气地回来了?
With wounds too.
而且还受了这么多伤
I'm sorry.
对不起
If you have time to apologize,
你有时间道歉
Go and get Miyo-chan back right now.
不如现在就去接美世回来
I can't do that.
我做不到
Huh? What are you say--
什么?你在说...
I lost the duel.
我输了
I...
我...
don't have the right to get her back.
没有带美世走的资格
Ow!
好疼
Hey!
我说你
It doesn't matter what a loser like you thinks.
像你这样的废柴男的感受并不重要
You can't just leave poor Miyo-chan like that.
这样下去美世很可怜的
But Miyo wasn't sure...
但是美世说了
which one of us she should be with, me or Usuba.
她不知道
She said she didn't know.
该选我还是薄刃
You fool!
你这个傻瓜
Think harder about this situation.
你好好想想
No matter how harsh you were with her,
不过你以前对她有多严苛
you know she wouldn't say something like that for revenge.
她绝对不会因此来报复你
She blames herself.
她是怪自己
She thinks she was bad for not realizing how you feel.
她觉得没能体察你的感受是她的错
She wants so badly to stay by your side.
她非常想留在你身边
But she knows that if you turn her away, it's over.
可是她知道如果你推开她 就结束了
That's why she wanted to improve herself.
所以她想要提升自己
She wanted to be needed by you.
她想为你出一份力
Of course, she was afraid to confide in you.
她不能找你商量也是理所应当的吧
Then I guess...
我还是
I really made a big mistake.
做错了吗?
Pull yourself together!
振作起来
You are all she has.
你是她的全部
Understood. I'll be right over.
我知道了 我现在就去
I'm going to the headquarters.
我要去军部
You're kidding.
不是吧
Are you just going to ignore Miyo and go to work?
你要放任美世不管去工作吗?
An emergency situation has occurred.
出现紧急情况
But, that's not a reason to--
即便如此...
It's a matter of life or death for everybody.
情况紧急 事关人命
Suppose I treated my mission lightly, and there were casualties as a result.
如果我坐视不管 会有人牺牲
That would most certainly make Miyo blame herself.
那美世绝对不会原谅自己
So I have to go.
所以我要去
When I'm done with everything, I'll bring back Miyo without fail.
等我终结这一切 我一定会去接美世
If that's how you feel, try to finish your work in a jiffy.
如果你是这么想的 就速战速决
Okay. I'm going now.
好 我去去就回
Wait for me, Miyo.
等着我 美世
Is anything the matter?
有什么事吗?
Maybe.
不好啊
I have an uneasy feeling...
我很不安
But I suppose all I can do now is believe.
但我现在只能选择相信
It's almost here.
很快
when everything that poses a threat to us will cease to exist.
威胁我等之人全部消失的 那天即将到来
They are finally approaching the imperial city?
他们终于要到帝都了吗?
Yes.
是啊
Please report to me the movements of the army as they happen.
请详细报告军队的动向
Right. Goodbye.
明白了 再见
If by any chance the Special Anti-grotesquerie Unit
万一对异特殊部队
can't stop the Grotesqueries...
没能阻止异形
What will happen to this imperial city?
帝都会变成什么样呢?
In any case, since Miyo is back here with the Usuba family,
只要美世回到薄刃家
I shall concentrate on performing my duty.
我只需要专心履行自己的职责
Hey, Grandfather?
祖父
What is it, Arata?
怎么了 新?
How long do I have to wait until I get my own duty?
我什么时候才能得到自己的使命?
I don't really know.
我也不知道
Well, don't worry.
不过不必担心
That day will certainly come in the future.
那一天终将到来
And you will have a job to do.
到那时 你会拥有
You will have a role only you can fill.
只有你才能完成的使命
That day has finally come.
这一天终于来了
Now I must do my job...
只有我
in a role only I can fill.
才能完成的使命
Yes.
请进
Ms. Miyo, how are you feeling?
美世小姐 你身体感觉如何?
Um, how is my husband-to-be?
请问 老爷呢?
Is he all right?
老爷没事吧?
All I did was send him out of our property with the barrier force.
我只是借用结界的力量将他赶了出去
He arrived home safely, and now he's back to work as usual, I heard.
他安全回家了 现在似乎在一如既往地工作
He sure is coldhearted.
他还真是冷酷无情
He chose his work over you.
比起你 他选择了工作
It turned out fine.
这样就好
Everything worked out as it should.
各归各位
This is how it's supposed to be.
本应如此
Oh?
什么?
Mother...
母亲
Ms. Sumi had the supernatural ability to connect with people's minds.
澄美阿姨拥有能够连接人心的异能
She had telepathy.
精神感应
What?
什么?
She was able to transmit thoughts into people's minds.
她能将思想转达到别人心中
And it is said that a child of the wielder of that ability
拥有这种异能的人的孩子
sometimes develops unusually rare supernatural abilities.
可能会拥有非常稀有的异能
And that's the ability you have,
那就是你的异能
Dream-Sight.
梦见之力
So actually, what I described to Mr. Kudo
其实我对久堂先生说的
was only just a part of Dream-Sight.
只是梦见之力的一小部分
What?
什么?
Dream-Sight ability is the power to enter any individual's mind while they sleep
梦见的异能能够潜入任何人的梦境中
and manipulate their dreams.
并操控他们的梦
All humans need to sleep.
这个世界上没有人不睡觉
So no matter how strong they are, their minds can be manipulated
所以无论面对多么强大的人 都可以操纵他们的精神
or even be brainwashed.
洗脑他们
But that's not all.
不止这些
As your Dream-Sight improves, you'll be able to see in your dreams,
如果力量进一步升级 就能在梦中
the past, present, and future.
见到过去、现在、未来
All of time could be viewed.
能够浏览所有的时光
Such a powerful ability...
我怎么会有
And I have it...?
这么强大的异能?
Excuse me
对不起
for giving you so much information all at once.
一下子告诉你这么多事
Then why...
为什么
didn't my supernatural ability awaken until now?
我从前没能觉醒异能呢?
There is a reason for that.
事出有因
It's because someone sealed off your supernatural ability.
因为有人封印了你的异能
Sealed off? Who would do such a thing?
封印?是谁?
It was your mother, Sumi, that sealed off your ability.
是你的母亲澄美
Mother?
母亲?
Why did Mother do that?
母亲为什么要这么做?
I'll have to start the story
如果要说这个
from just before you were born...
就要追溯到
for me to explain the reason.
你出生之前的事了
I'll tell you everything.
我会告诉你一切
I'll tell you why Sumi married into the Saimori family,
为什么澄美会嫁入斋森家
and why she sealed off your supernatural ability.
并且封印了你的异能
Subtitle translation by: Ikuko Ohno
字幕翻译:郭宁